### **Gareth Carter**

**Mobile:** 0750 503 4878

**Email:** gareth-carter@outlook.com **Portfolio:** www.garethcarter.com/portfolio



### **Personal Statement**

Working with digital artwork is my core area of expertise, be it creation, manipulation or preparation for publication or print. Being in an environment of creativity, developing new skills, and continuing to grow in the artworking and graphic design professions, inspires and motivates me in all aspects of my life.

### **Skillset**

- PC & Mac literate
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Acrobat

- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Photoshop
- Full and clean driving licence since 2009 and own transport

### **Employment**

2021 - present:

# Oadby and Wigston Borough Council: Community & Wellbeing Community Champion (Design)

- Designing supplementary material for targeted health messages and campaigns in print and on social media (using provided resources, such as text content and logos), including self-created illustrations and other graphic design elements
- Adherence to brand guidelines, such as fonts, layout and colour palettes with additional creative leeway in certain projects
- Recreating low resolution raster logos as vectors in Illustrator so that they can be easily scaled without losing resolution quality

2018 - 2020:

#### **Data Image Group Ltd.**

## Artworker – GQA Level 3 NVQ Diploma in 'Digital Pre-Press in the Process and Manufacturing Sector'

- Exposure to all of the company's pre-press production and artwork with a wide variety of jobs including packaging, labels, billboards, and point-of-sale signage such as posters, roller banners and display units
- Extensive use of the Adobe Creative Suite and I-Cut Preflight:
  - Illustrator: a large range of functions including adding cut, kiss cut and crease lines, resizing and rearranging artwork elements
  - Acrobat and I-Cut Preflight: less intrusive editing of client-supplied PDFs to reduce the risk of unexpected changes that might go undetected
  - Photoshop: artworking raster elements, including tools such as 'magic wand' and the 'channels' tab
  - InDesign: creating and artworking flyers and brochures. Creating data merges for batches of labels sequentially numbered

- Available jobs, selected daily through the project management software, were prioritised according to estimator details. It was necessary to manage multiple jobs at once if any were put on hold whilst waiting for approval or revised artwork
- Quality control of client-supplied, in-house and self-designed artwork, ensuring brand guidelines were met and achievable within print production constraints
- Liaising with colleagues and clients in respect of queries, PDF approvals etc.
  - On more than one occasion, my strong attention to detail was invaluable. For example, I contacted the client when an artwork variant did not match the brand guidelines, they agreed with my analysis, were able to make the adjustments, and resupply the artwork in time for the print deadline
- If a design or production problem arose, I was keen to find a resolution and was not afraid to share ideas
- During busy periods or tight deadlines, there was a strong sense of teamwork and a willingness to support one another within and across departments, for example, by sharing pre-press workload and helping with administration or packing. Sometimes I remained after contracted hours to finish my part in a job if it helped later production stages meet their deadlines
- All job-related files and templates were appropriately named and stored in a consistent folder structure. Eager to learn new skills, I took on the responsibility for selecting appropriate folders to archive to tape, typically files older than 3 months, and scheduling the archives to run at convenient times
- Adherence to health & safety regulations
- Operating and troubleshooting a proof printer
- Whilst specialising in digital print, day release sessions covered the theory behind various print processes, such as lithography and letterpress

#### 2014 - present:

### <u>Freelance – 'Gareth Carter Digital Artist'</u>

## Digital geometric art created in Photoshop and Illustrator as a hobby and for commission

- For example, my 'Album Art Re-Imagined' project has developed into commissions for musicians. Important aspects include:
  - Working with the client in developing artwork including negotiating edit suggestions, proof reading the final product and contract creation
  - Meeting the tight release date deadlines
- Experience in typography creation and an understanding of what makes an appropriate and effective typeface

#### **Education and Qualifications**

**Learn 2 Print:** GQA Level 3 NVQ Diploma in 'Digital Pre-Press in the Process and Manufacturing Sector'

**De Montfort University:** BA (hons) in Photography and Video

Beauchamp College: 2 A Levels, 9 GCSEs (C and above including English &

Maths)